Finding Aid for the Karen Filter photographs LSC.2432
UCLA Library Special Collections
Karen Filter photographs
1979-1985
UCLA Library Special Collections
Filter, Karen
LSC.2432
0.9 linear feet (1 box)
Karen Filter is a photographer who documented the Los Angeles punk scene from 1979-1985. Originally from Canton, Ohio, she attended college at UCLA and received a B.A. in Fine Arts in 1976, and later attended the Brooks Institute of Photography where she received a professional photography degree in 1978. Materials consist of 22 black and white silver gelatin prints and 3 Resin Coated prints which document the Los Angeles punk scene from 1979-1985. These images capture performers and scene makers across Los Angeles and provide documentation of historic venues such as Hong Kong Cafe, New Wave Theater, Whisky-a-Go-Go, and Club 88.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Karen Filter, 2022.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9996911713506533
Biographical / Historical
Karen Filter is a photographer who documented the Los Angeles punk scene from 1979-1985. Originally from Canton, Ohio, she attended college at UCLA and received a B.A. in Fine Arts in 1976, and later attended the Brooks Institute of Photography where she received a professional photography degree in 1978. She's exhibited her work at The Photography Center of Los Angeles in 1983, as well as at The Gallery on La Brea Ave, in Los Angeles in 1990. Her work has also been exhibited in group shows at the Zero One Gallery (1985), Center of Photography at Woodstock (1993), and LACE, Live in LA (2011). Karen's photographs have been featured in three books: Hardcore California, 1982, 24 Hours in the Life of Los Angeles, 1984, and 8 Visions, 1988. Her work has also been featured in various magazines and on record covers.
Scope and Contents
The Karen Filter photographs consist of 22 black and white silver gelatin prints and 3 Resin Coated prints which document the Los Angeles punk scene from 1979-1985. These images capture performers and scene makers across Los Angeles and provide documentation of historic venues such as Hong Kong Cafe, New Wave Theater, Whisky-a-Go-Go, and Club 88.
Arrangement
The collection's arrangement maintains its existing order.
Filter, Karen
- Bob / Punk, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ann / Punk, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Photographed on the street in LA.
- Stiv Bators, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographed at the New Wave Theater in LA.
- Jello Biafra of Dead Kennedys, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- FEAR, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographed at a San Fernando Valley rehearsal studio. (L-R) Spit Stix, Derf Scratch, Philo Cramer, and Lee Ving.
- The Plugz, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Weirdos, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  (L-R) John Denney, Cliff Martinez, Cliff Roman, and Dix Denney photographed backstage at the Whisky-a-Go-Go.
- Exene Cervenka of X, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographed at the Whisky-a-Go-Go in LA.
- John Doe of X, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- FEAR, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographed in a parking lot in San Fernando Valley. (L-R) Philo Cramer, Derf Scratch, Lee Ving, and Spit Stix.
- 45 Grave, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  (L-R) Dinah Cancer, Rob Graves, Don Bolles, Paul Cutler
- Peter Ivers and regulars with Dead Kennedys, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jeffery Lee Pierce of The Gun Club, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Keith Morris of the Circle Jerks, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Peter Ivers with the Circle Jerks, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographed at the New Wave Theater in LA. (L-R) Lucky Lehrer, Keith Morris, "Peter Ivers", Roger Rogerson, Greg Hetson
- Speed Queen / performance artist, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographed at the Hong Kong Cafe in LA.
- The Flesh Eaters, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The (Original) Go-Go's, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photographed at Club 88 in LA. (L-R) Charlotte Caffey, Elissa Bello, Belinda Carlisle, Margot Olavarria, Jane Wiedlin.
- Attila, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Hairdresser on Melrose.
- Stiv Bators, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Legal Weapon, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photographed on a rooftop in Downtown LA.
- Dead Kennedys, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Henry Rollins of Black Flag, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photographed in Karen's studio.
- Margot Olavarria - founder of The Go-Go's, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photographed at Club 88 in LA.
- Attila / famous hairdresser, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photographed at a salon on Melrose. Attila (silver teeth) pictured with Tequila Mockingbird and other clientele.